<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Michael Pallister</title>
 <link href="http://micp.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://micp.co.uk/"/>
 <updated>2013-04-02T08:01:01+01:00</updated>
 <id>http://micp.co.uk/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Michael Pallister</name>
   <email>michael@micp.co.uk</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Old vs New</title>
   <link href="http://www.micp.co.uk/2013/03/23/old-vs-new"/>
   <updated>2013-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://micp.co.uk/2013/03/23/old-vs-new</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It may be just me but as soon as I see a website I like the look of I open firebug and hit refresh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I look at how many requests it's making, followed by the page size, page load time and it's Google page speed rank. I understand some sites are larger than others but there's nothing I can't stand more than waiting for a page to load.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of this I wanted to compare my old site to the new one and you can see the results in the table below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;post-table&quot;&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;post-table-column&quot;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;post-table-column&quot;&gt;Old&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;post-table-column&quot;&gt;New&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;post-table-row-alt&quot;&gt;Page requests&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;post-table-row-alt&quot;&gt;21&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;post-table-row-alt&quot;&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;post-table-row&quot;&gt;Page size&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;post-table-row&quot;&gt;300KB&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;post-table-row&quot;&gt;79.2KB&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;post-table-row-alt&quot;&gt;Page load time&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;post-table-row-alt&quot;&gt;5.43s&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;post-table-row-alt&quot;&gt;0.81s&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see from the results above there is a massive difference. Both sites were extremely text heavy but there's a few differences between the two. I am no longer using images on the homepage under each post title and the new site isn't loading in my Instragram pictures or trakt.tv stats. Whilst I do plan to add both of these to this site I also plan to re-write the code I was using for both to ensure that the site loading time stays extremely quick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've still got a few things like adding expiry headers but due to github not liking htaccess files I'm going to have to look at doing this another way but for the minute I'm happy with a page loading time that is under a second!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Moving to Jekyll</title>
   <link href="http://www.micp.co.uk/2013/03/22/moving-to-jekyll"/>
   <updated>2013-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://micp.co.uk/2013/03/22/moving-to-jekyll</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my first update here for a long time! There's a few reasons why I've not updated and the main one is because I had fell out of love with what I'd previously built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wordpress was my CMS/blog platform of choice for a number of years and I'd spent an awful lot of my time learning the ins and outs of it. Over time I'd realised it wasn't for anyone elses benefit but my own. Sure I could install Wordpress, skin the install to look how I wanted, install a few plugins and if I really needed to create my own widgets but did I really need all this to build a blog were all I needed to do was posts a few articles?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember when I first installed Wordpress. That feeling of something &quot;new&quot; and different. Something I'd never saw before and something I was eager to learn. It was a great feeling but over time as Wordpress has grew I've realised I don't need to grow with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason I'd stopped blogging is because I was spending my time trying to build something better than what I already had. I consider myself one of those people who are never really satisfied with anything, I know I'm destined to live my life unfulfilled. I believe if you ask any designer or developer the majority of them will probably say something along the same lines. If I had the luxury to go back and re-write everything I've done once I had completed the task I probably would. However, if I did this I'd never actually get anything done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One night I was messing around in the browser creating a new blog design (I might release this as a freebie at a later point) when I thought to myself - &quot;Do I really need Wordpress?&quot; - I mean, I only really share my thoughts and a little code here and there. This is the exact point when I decided to look in to using something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd considered all the other CMS platforms out there and installed quite a few of them but they seemed as bulky as Wordpress. I didn't need or want this. I even went to the extent of building my own login system which came from the idea of creating my own little CMS but once again I didn't really love the idea and after a few days of playing around with it I decided it wasn't something I wanted to do when there's so many good, small CMS systems out there already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Jekyll&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few weeks of looking around I came across Jekyll thanks to Harry Roberts at &lt;a href=&quot;http://csswizardry.com&quot;&gt;CSS Wizardy&lt;/a&gt;. I'd noticed one day that my RSS reader was telling me that I'd not read all the articles on his site. Something which at the time I knew wasn't true. I cleared the unread notifications from my reader and fired his site up in my browser. I instantly noticed he'd redesigned but what caught my eye the most was a little message in his footer - &quot;Built with inuit.css and Jekyll. The source code of this blog is hosted on GitHub&quot;. I instantly clicked on the link and went to his github page to look at his code and noticed that the structure of his website was set up in a way I'd never seen before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20 minutes later and a little look around Google I had discovered &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Initial thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was impressed. Jekyll was going to give me back control of my blog with static files. No longer did I need a database to store my posts or an admin system that I had to update every few weeks when Wordpress rolled out their updates. All I needed to do was install Jekyll and use my github account to host the website. I thought I'd be up and running with a new blog within days! The reality however was it has taken me a few month to finally start using Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why did it take so long?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few reasons; mostly because I've been doing other things and didn't have the time. I was reading up on Jekyll as much as I could over the weeks but it wasn't until a few weeks ago when I noticed that &lt;a href=&quot;http://toddmotto.com&quot;&gt;Todd Motto&lt;/a&gt; had also moved his website to Jekyll that I finally decided to put some time aside and get my hands dirty!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;So here I am&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a week or so of designing in the broswer, focusing on mobile first and multiple deaths on the new Tomb Raider game my new blog is now up and running. I much prefer the clean feel to this than anything else I've ever built for myself. I also enjoy the ease of navigation on both desktop and mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Hosting on Github?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes! I found it a little hard to believe when I first realised I could do this too. My current hosting package is literally about to run out (26th March 2013) which is another reason I've decided to make the switch. I'll be getting some cheap hosting so that if I am ever building something and need to use a database I have that option there but I'll definitely be saving myself a little each year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;So what now?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good question, I always find myself messing around with code. I believe the best way to learn something is to do it - reading books only gets you so far. My plan is to use this blog to release things I've built (starting with my &lt;a href=&quot;http://trakt.tv&quot;&gt;trakt.tv script&lt;/a&gt;) as well as other little bits and pieces that I find myself trying. I might also add the functionality for users to add comments so I can get a little feedback on my articles but for the time being. I'm happy to be back and using Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Apple TV jailbreak</title>
   <link href="http://www.micp.co.uk/2012/11/apple-tv-jailbreak/"/>
   <updated>2012-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://micp.co.uk/2012/11/apple-tv-jailbreak</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ve finally got myself an Apple TV 2 after finding out you couldn’t jailbreak the v3 one! I picked one up on eBay for a good price which came with 5.1 installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anyone has read up on these devices they’ll know what the “hockey puck” can do when it’s been jailbroken. You’ll also know that a device on 5.1 (iOS6) can’t be jailbroken. I knew this when I bought this off eBay but I also knew Apple where still signing the 5.0.2 firmware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First thing I did was download the 5.0.2 ipsw and restore the device back to this firmware – then just use the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.appletvhacks.net/2012/06/06/how-to-jailbreak-apple-tv-2-5-0-2-ios-5-1-1-using-seas0npass-untethered/&quot;&gt;guide&lt;/a&gt; here to jailbreak the device using Seas0nPass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I’d got the device jailbroken I then installed Nito TV. To do this you will first need to find out the IP address of your Apple TV. You can find this in settings &gt; about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have that open terminal (or any other command line program) and enter the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ssh&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;root&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@IPADDRESS&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;You should then be prompted for your password. The default password as for the majority of Apple devices is alpine. Once you’ve entered this you’ll get a little message which you just need to type yes to then press enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you should of SSH’d on to your device. First you’ll need to update all your packages. To do this type:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;apt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;update&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Once that’s done type:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;apt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;install&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nito&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nitoTV&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This will then install Nito TV on your Apple TV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can then go ahead and kill the session using:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;killall&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;AppleTV&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;You should now be able to reconnect your Apple TV to your TV and see Nito TV is installed – this will allow you to install a number of other things – mostly importantly I think; XBMC.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New domains</title>
   <link href="http://www.micp.co.uk/2012/10/new-domains/"/>
   <updated>2012-10-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://micp.co.uk/2012/10/new-domains</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a quick post to let everyone know I can be found at two more domains! Whilst at work on my lunch I decided to purchase www.michael-pallister.co.uk and www.michael-pallister.com.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>iPhone5 ownership</title>
   <link href="http://www.micp.co.uk/2012/10/iphone5-ownership/"/>
   <updated>2012-10-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://micp.co.uk/2012/10/iphone5-ownership</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ve had my iPhone5 for a little while now and after having a few doubts when I upgraded I’m now glad I made the jump from my iPhone4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phone arrived and the first thing I noticed was the new slimmer packaging the iPhone came in. I’ve always been amazed by Apples packaging and how everything seems so thought through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I’d opened it and turned the device on the transfer of my back up was extremely quick. The new lightening cable seems to transfer data quicker than the old one – I’ve not actually looked whether this is true though so it could just be all my imagination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first things I instantly noticed was the weight difference from the iPhone4. This thing is a lot lighter and seems to fit my hand a lot better. Coupled with the new aluminum back I think these small changes make the phone better than the previous versions whilst still maintaining that style which we all associate with an Apple device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The larger screen is a welcome addition to the phone and coupled with iOS6 there’s a large amount of new features. I’ve used to new Maps App once and successfully got to my destination so I’m not sure what all the fuss is about! My favorite new feature is Do not disturb – I’ve set it so from 23:00 – 07:00 my phone doesn’t pop up with any notifications to wake my when I’m trying to sleep – this means no more notifications of spam following me at 4am from Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I love my new iPhone like a love every Apple device I own. I couldn’t imagine myself using another phone simply because everything is so simple and well thought out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing I am missing is the Jailbreak which I’m sure will come soon and another cable for work! However on that note I have just ordered a micro-usb to lightening adapter direct from Apple which can be seen &lt;a href=&quot;http://store.apple.com/uk/product/MD820ZM/A/lightning-to-micro-usb-adapter?fnode=48&quot; title=&quot;Micro USB to Lightening&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Sublime Text 2</title>
   <link href="http://www.micp.co.uk/2012/09/sublime-text-2/"/>
   <updated>2012-09-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://micp.co.uk/2012/09/sublime-text-2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started my new job I was faced with using Dreamweaver again for the first time in years. I’d left Dreamweaver at MX version and since used PHPEdit, Coda and Aptana for my coding UI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my previous blog post stated my new job was coding in Coldfusion and my UI of choice at the time was Aptana Studio which didn’t support .cfm or .cfc files which Coldfusion uses so I was forced with using Dreamweaver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The white background slowly started to give me a headache. I’d been used to coding on a dark background for some time and found it a lot easier so after coming home one night with a massive headache I decided to have a look around to see if there was a program I could use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of thing suggested Eclipse which was also built for developing using Coldfusion but then I stumbled across Sublime Text 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a swift download I opened my first .cfm file and noticed that there was no syntax highlighting. Back to square one I thought but it wasn’t! Another quick search of Google provided me with some instructions on how to enable Coldfusion support in Sublime Text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now Sublime Text is a an extremely light text-editor which loads in seconds (don’t believe me? Download it and see) but the extensions that are available for it are amazing and allow so much more which is why I’ve switched to the editor at home and work. There’s also a handy plugin which uses dropbox to sync your users folder so any files you have open in one location will open in the other. I’ve not gone this far because I like to keep my work and home work separate but this would be a nice feature for anyone who doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download Sublime Text &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sublimetext.com/&quot; title=&quot;Download Sublime Text&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;
Once downloaded I suggest the first thing you do is install the package manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://wbond.net/sublime_packages/package_control/installation&quot; title=&quot;Install Sublime Text package manager&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and it’s as simple as opening Sublime Text and pasting the code in to the console window.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A week coding in ColdFusion</title>
   <link href="http://www.micp.co.uk/2012/09/a-week-coding-in-coldfusion/"/>
   <updated>2012-09-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://micp.co.uk/2012/09/a-week-coding-in-coldfusion</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I started my job this week working at Teesside University. This wasn’t the only thing new in my life this week. As I logged on to my machine – set everything up to how I like it I began the familiar task of looking around the files to see exactly how the Universities website was built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staring back at me was a language which looked totally new – ColdFusion. Now my previous experience of ColdFusion was that program I never opened that came with Macromedia’s MX suite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After looking around a few files things starts to look familiar. I could see how variables were set. I could see if’s, loops and queries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been 4 days since I looked at my first ColdFusion file – the methods are the same as many other languages I’ve used over the years but it’s a whole new way of doing things and I’m really enjoying the change and challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the perks to my new job is that I have access to the Universities library. A quick search on their system returned 10 books related a ColdFusion and a short walk later I had picked up a copy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://compare.ebay.co.uk/like/330789889051?var=lv&amp;amp;ltyp=AllFixedPriceItemTypes&amp;amp;var=sbar&amp;amp;cbt=y&quot;&gt;Adobe ColdFusion 8, Getting Started&lt;/a&gt; (link is to an eBay auction I found were the book is insanely cheap).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’ve read around about the first 100 pages and it deals with installation of ColdFusion and using the ColdFusion admin which makes connecting to databases extremely easy due the simple UI you’re presented with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping to finish most of the book by next week so I can get a better grasp on the language. I’d certainly recommend it to anyone wanting to try something new simply due to the fact I’m enjoying it myself!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Goodbye, thank you and the next chapter</title>
   <link href="http://www.micp.co.uk/2012/09/goodbye-thank-you-and-the-next-chapter/"/>
   <updated>2012-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://micp.co.uk/2012/09/goodbye-thank-you-and-the-next-chapter</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never really been one for saying goodbye. I like to think that the friends you make along the way will be friends forever and if your paths cross again it’s an excuse to catch up over a few beers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now as many of you reading this probably know, I start my new job tomorrow at Teesside University. After 2 years of being at Visualsoft it was a hard choice but one I had to make to further my career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the 2 years I’ve made some awesome friends, made a lot of good memories and ate my way through a lot of fat Fridays! Due to these people I’d highly recommend Visualsoft to anyone looking for an e-commerce website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d also like to say thanks for my &lt;a href=&quot;http://store.apple.com/uk/product/H1453ZM/A&quot;&gt;Incase Compact Backpack&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve already used it on my little trip to Apple to get my iPhone sorted and it works a treat!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Diet: Part 2</title>
   <link href="http://www.micp.co.uk/2012/08/diet-part-2/"/>
   <updated>2012-08-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://micp.co.uk/2012/08/diet-part-2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anybody who knows me well enough will know I enjoy nothing more than eating food. They will also know that at the end of April I decided to go on a little diet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’ve never had to diet before this. I’ve never cared about what I ate. Calories I consumed and all of that. I’ve just ate what I want, when I want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In January I had another operation on my left knee. This was a small operation to repair the cartilage in the knee but one that would mean I wouldn’t exercise for 4 months due to my previous knee injuries and one that meant I wouldn’t kick a ball until 2 weeks ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April I decided to up my rehab. I had previously been doing light weight work at the gym to build up the supporting muscles but this wasn’t contributing to any weight loss and I was still eating like I used to so I then decided I needed to loose some of the weight I had gained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my amazement I had put on just under a stone in the few months I had not been doing any exercise and eating rubbish constantly. This has took me to an all time high weight of 14st 7lbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d done a lot of research in to diets and tried a few which resulted in me losing 3lbs in 2/3 weeks but losing a pound a week wasn’t quick enough for my enjoyment and I was back to the drawing board. I finally found a diet in which I would need to cut all forms of carbs down to a minimal. I’d never looked on the back of a packet before as to what is in the products but as far as I could see everything contained carbs!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first 4/5 days were a major struggle as my body was running low on stored carbs which you body essentially uses for energy. After this though your body will start to burn fat for energy which is how you begin to lose weight. I coupled my new diet with 1/2 nights of weight work at the gym and 2/3 nights of running on the streets which saw me drop from 14st 4lbs to 12st 4lbs (start of July 2012) which meant I had lost in total around 2 and a half stone in weight in a short time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may now be wondering why it says Diet: Part 2 in the title? Well; after losing the weight I went on an all inclusive holiday which basically is saying “come eat and drink all day whilst laying in the sun” and I did exactly that. I have now been home around 2 weeks and I’ve continued to eat carbs and I am once again waking up feeling a little more tired than I did when I didn’t eat them. I’m also waking up a lot during the night and my sleeping pattern is rubbish – all of which I didn’t have problems with when I wasn’t eating carbs. I am currently at a weight of 12st 10lbs which means I’ve gained 6lbs in 4/5 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ve decided that as of tomorrow (Thursday 9th August) I will be adapting my diet again to remove the carbs. I wont be as strict as I previously was because I am only looking to lose around a stone in weight over a 2/3 month period but I will definitely be watching my daily carb intake and exercising more. All of which I will blog on here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app (MyFitnessPal) I am currently using to log my daily food intake doesn’t have an API so if anyone knows of one which does then please let me know. I’d be happy to have a play around and build something which I can then place on the site to monitor my current weight / total weight loss (hopefully) daily intake and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>1140 CSS Grid</title>
   <link href="http://www.micp.co.uk/2012/08/1140-css-grid/"/>
   <updated>2012-08-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://micp.co.uk/2012/08/1140-css-grid</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responsive Web Design is a big thing in the web world at the minute. Having a website which responds to the resolution of the device it’s being viewed on is going to be standard practice soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time we only had to design for desktop so websites which were wrapped in a container were fine. Now we have a range of devices that users can access the content from:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Desktop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tablets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile phones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I could sit and write all day about how it’s now important to serve up a different design for these 3 devices but I’m sure the majority of you already know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have had a few people ask me if I’ve used a CSS framework and the answer is yes. After looking at a few different frameworks I finally settled on the 1140 CSS Grid (&lt;a href=&quot;http://cssgrid.net/&quot; title=&quot;CSS  Grid&quot;&gt;cssgrid.net&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The grid is built up of 12 columns which all adapt depending on what the user has as their resolution. You’re able to choose a variety of different column choices for your layout as long as the column count adds up to 12.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for an example my header is currently 8×4 columns and my footer is currently 4x4x4 which all equal 12.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for a responsive framework to get your website up and running quickly then I’d suggest that you go and take a look at the 1140 grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also a WordPress theme which is available &lt;a href=&quot;http://dotma.cc/8Yqk&quot; title=&quot;1140 WordPress theme&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; which is what I am using. This will basically strip your theme down to plain text and allow you to build it up from there. A little bit of knowledge about WordPress is required though. If you decide to use the framework and have any questions just pop me an email (address in the footer).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Trakt.tv</title>
   <link href="http://www.micp.co.uk/2012/08/trakt-tv/"/>
   <updated>2012-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://micp.co.uk/2012/08/trakt-tv</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anybody who knows me well enough will know that I spend a large amount of my free time watching movies and TV series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few year ago I built myself a HTPC (Home Theatre PC). It basically looks like a DVD player but works like a computer. The PC runs Ubuntu and has XBMC (XBOX Media Centre) installed along with a few other plugins to make my life easier and to make sure that my library of TV shows is always up to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now a few month back I was using a plugin called goMiso to record everything I watched – I liked the social aspect of the plugin. Being able to see what other people where watching and vice-versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That plugin however slowly became a massive pain to me. It would frequently crash, not load on startup or record that I was watching NULL on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This made me start to look around for an alternative which is where I came across &lt;a href=&quot;http://trakt.tv/user/micp&quot; title=&quot;My Trakt profile&quot;&gt;trakt.tv&lt;/a&gt;. After singing up and installing a few plugins I found this to be just what I needed. The plugin crawled my library and pulled in everything I had marked as watched, this then allowed me to logon to the site and see what other people where watching who had watched similar movies and tv series to myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using Trakt for many months now without any issues. On startup it checks both my Movies and TV libraries for newly added / updated items and displays a nice little tweet when I start watching something so all my friends know what I’m up too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look over to the right on the homepage you will now see I’ve added a recently watched section. I am basically making a call to the trakt API and pulling in my most recently watched with a few lines of code (I will share this at a later date once I’ve added a few more bits and pieces).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, if anybody is looking for somewhere social where they can share their media collections and find new movies and tv shows or old one’s which you may have forgotten about then I definitely recommend you check out trakt.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>iPhone5 &#8211; September launch?</title>
   <link href="http://www.micp.co.uk/2012/07/iphone5-september-launch/"/>
   <updated>2012-07-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://micp.co.uk/2012/07/iphone5-september-launch</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seems to be that time of the year again. When the gossip about the new iPhone goes in to over-drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do a google search for “iPhone5″ you will definitely get a massive amount of results all telling you something similar. The current rumours are that the 5 will be released in September – not October as the 4S was previously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This falls perfectly in line with my phone contract upgrade so I’ll be getting myself one. It will be interesting to see what Apple put in their latest phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talk has been that the iPhone5 will contain a quad-core processor and come with 4g technology (not that we can make use of it in the UK yet!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phone will be shipping with IOS6 which will also be available for older Apple devices. If you’re keeping your old iPhone and updating to IOS6 it might be worth leaving it 48 hours before you try and update. After my IOS5 update experience and problems I won’t be updating the iPhone4 I have straight away!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a few leaked shots of a production version of the iPhone5. It seems to be the width of the current metal band around the iPhone5. Has a different connector dock on the bottom which is causing a lot of manufacturers a little headache although I expect Apple to maybe ship with phone with an adapter so you can still connect the device to all old connection ports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2012/07/iphone-1.jpg&quot; title=&quot;iPhone5 - Image 1&quot; alt=&quot;iPhone5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2012/07/iphone-13.jpg&quot; title=&quot;iPhone 5 - image 2.&quot; alt=&quot;iPhone5 - image 2.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Holiday!</title>
   <link href="http://www.micp.co.uk/2012/07/holiday/"/>
   <updated>2012-07-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://micp.co.uk/2012/07/holiday</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well after many months of waiting (and a trip to Barcelona in between) tomorrow is finally the day I go on holiday!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m of to Tenerife for 7 days! I am staying &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thomson.co.uk/destinations/europe/spain/tenerife/costa-adeje/hotels/costa-adeje-gran.html&quot; title=&quot;Costa Adeje - Gran Hotel&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if anybody is actually interested. I’ve also just noticed the search button on the left; someone at Thomson is having a bad day there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never been to Tenerife before and I enjoy going to new places so I’m looking forward to that. The fact it’s all inclusive also helps a little because I can sit in the sun all day drinking as much and eating as much as I want (this is going to ruin my recent diet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all holidays the best (and worst) photo’s will be available online for everyone to take a look. I’ll shot a link up once I’m back and I have had time to process them all.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Hello world!</title>
   <link href="http://www.micp.co.uk/2012/07/hello-world/"/>
   <updated>2012-07-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://micp.co.uk/2012/07/hello-world</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After many different versions, changes and directions I have finally settled on a design which I like for my portfolio/blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially these were going to be two different things but after much thought I decided to stick them together. I can now blog my findings and showcase my portfolio of work in the same place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to anyone who cares – the site is also responsive. So either fire up for your mobile phone or resize the browser window!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>