<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Michael Pallister</title>
 <link href="http://micp.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://micp.co.uk/"/>
 <updated>2013-03-22T17:07:02+00:00</updated>
 <id>http://micp.co.uk/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Michael Pallister</name>
   <email>michael@micp.co.uk</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Moving to Jekyll</title>
   <link href="http://www.micp.co.uk/2013/03/22/moving-to-jekyll.html"/>
   <updated>2013-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://micp.co.uk/2013/03/22/moving-to-jekyll</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my first update here for a long time! There's a few reasons why I've not updated and the main one is because I had fell out of love with what I'd previously built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wordpress was my CMS/blog platform of choice for a number of years and I'd spent an awful lot of my time learning the ins and outs of it. Over time I'd realised it wasn't for anyone elses benefit but my own. Sure I could install Wordpress, skin the install to look how I wanted, install a few plugins and if I really needed to create my own widgets but did I really need all this to build a blog were all I needed to do was posts a few articles?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember when I first installed Wordpress. That feeling of something &quot;new&quot; and different. Something I'd never saw before and something I was eager to learn. It was a great feeling but over time as Wordpress has grew I've realised I don't need to grow with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason I'd stopped blogging is because I was spending my time trying to build something better than what I already had. I consider myself one of those people who are never really satisfied with anything, I know I'm destined to live my life unfulfilled. I believe if you ask any designer or developer the majority of them will probably say something along the same lines. If I had the luxury to go back and re-write everything I've done once I had completed the task I probably would. However, if I did this I'd never actually get anything done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One night I was messing around in the browser creating a new blog design (I might release this as a freebie at a later point) when I thought to myself - &quot;Do I really need Wordpress?&quot; - I mean, I only really share my thoughts and a little code here and there. This is the exact point when I decided to look in to using something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd considered all the other CMS platforms out there and installed quite a few of them but they seemed as bulky as Wordpress. I didn't need or want this. I even went to the extent of building my own login system which came from the idea of creating my own little CMS but once again I didn't really love the idea and after a few days of playing around with it I decided it wasn't something I wanted to do when there's so many good, small CMS systems out there already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Jekyll&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few weeks of looking around I came across Jekyll thanks to Harry Roberts at &lt;a href=&quot;http://csswizardry.com&quot;&gt;CSS Wizardy&lt;/a&gt;. I'd noticed one day that my RSS reader was telling me that I'd not read all the articles on his site. Something which at the time I knew wasn't true. I cleared the unread notifications from my reader and fired his site up in my browser. I instantly noticed he'd redesigned but what caught my eye the most was a little message in his footer - &quot;Built with inuit.css and Jekyll. The source code of this blog is hosted on GitHub&quot;. I instantly clicked on the link and went to his github page to look at his code and noticed that the structure of his website was set up in a way I'd never seen before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20 minutes later and a little look around Google I had discovered &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Initial thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was impressed. Jekyll was going to give me back control of my blog with static files. No longer did I need a database to store my posts or an admin system that I had to update every few weeks when Wordpress rolled out their updates. All I needed to do was install Jekyll and use my github account to host the website. I thought I'd be up and running with a new blog within days! The reality however was it has taken me a few month to finally start using Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why did it take so long?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few reasons; mostly because I've been doing other things and didn't have the time. I was reading up on Jekyll as much as I could over the weeks but it wasn't until a few weeks ago when I noticed that &lt;a href=&quot;http://toddmotto.com&quot;&gt;Todd Motto&lt;/a&gt; had also moved his website to Jekyll that I finally decided to put some time aside and get my hands dirty!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;So here I am&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a week or so of designing in the broswer, focusing on mobile first and multiple deaths on the new Tomb Raider game my new blog is now up and running. I much prefer the clean feel to this than anything else I've ever built for myself. I also enjoy the ease of navigation on both desktop and mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Hosting on Github?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes! I found it a little hard to believe when I first realised I could do this too. My current hosting package is literally about to run out (26th March 2013) which is another reason I've decided to make the switch. I'll be getting some cheap hosting so that if I am ever building something and need to use a database I have that option there but I'll definitely be saving myself a little each year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;So what now?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good question, I always find myself messing around with code. I believe the best way to learn something is to do it - reading books only gets you so far. My plan is to use this blog to release things I've built (starting with my &lt;a href=&quot;http://trakt.tv&quot;&gt;trakt.tv script&lt;/a&gt;) as well as other little bits and pieces that I find myself trying. I might also add the functionality for users to add comments so I can get a little feedback on my articles but for the time being. I'm happy to be back and using Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>